Preliminary Inventory of the O. Ė. Tuganova papers
Hoover Institution Archives
O. Ė. Tuganova papers
1906-2006
90086
Tuganova, O. Ė.
12 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (5.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoirs, diaries, poems, other writings, certificates, and photograph, relating to political and cultural conditions in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia, Russian literature, purges in the Soviet Union during the 1930s, and the execution for anti-Soviet activities in 1938 of Edgar Polents, father of O. Ė. Tuganova, and his posthumous rehabilitation in 1956.
Administrative Information
Access
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Russian social scientist.
Scope and Content of Collection
Memoirs, diaries, poems, other writings, certificates, and photograph, relating to political and cultural conditions in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia, Russian literature, purges in the Soviet Union during the 1930s, and the execution for anti-Soviet activities in 1938 of Edgar Polents, father of O. Ė. Tuganova, and his posthumous rehabilitation in 1956.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Polents, Edgar Ivanovich, 1891-1938.; Political purges--Soviet Union.; Political crimes and offenses--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--Civilization.; Soviet Union--Politics and government.; Soviet Union--Social conditions.; Russian literature.
Collection Contents
- Writings, certificates, and photograph, relating to purges in the Soviet Union during the 1930s; the execution for anti-Soviet activities in 1938 of Edgar Polents, father of O. E. Tuganova, and his posthumous rehabilitation in 1956; and memories of Moscow on the day of the German invasion of the Soviet Union, 1941 June 22. In Russian (Folder 1)
- Diaries, poems, and other writings, 1981-1992, relating to contemporary conditions and literature in the Soviet Union. Includes some writings by Vladimir Lazarev, husband of O. E. Tuganova. In Russian (Folder 1)
- Containing a genealogy of the Tuganov family, 1993; an interview by Vladimir Lazarev of Mother Lidia, a nun in Peredelkino, about Boris Pasternak's life in Peredelkino, 1992-1993; and a brochure on Vladimir Lazarev's work, 1993. In Russian (Folder 1)
- Memoirs, 1993, relating to contemporary conditions and literature in the Soviet Union. In Russian (Folder 2)
- Memoirs, 1994, relating to contemporary conditions and literature in the Soviet Union. In Russian (Folder 2)
- Writings, 1995, relating to social conditions in the Soviet Union and Russia. In Russian (Folder 3)
- Photograph, ca. 1906, of the Tuganov family (Folder 3)
- Memoirs, other writings, and biographical data, 1995-1997, relating to political and cultural conditions in Russia. In Russian and English (Folder 4)
- Memoirs of Vladimir Lazarev, n.d., relating to political and social conditions in Russia. In Russian (Folder 4)
- Diaries and printed matter, 1962-1995, relating to political and cultural conditions in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia. In Russian (Folder 5-6)
- Diaries, 1998, relating to political and cultural conditions in Russia. In Russian (Folder 5)
- Writings, 1998-2000, relating to the Tuganov family. Mainly in German (Folder 5)
- Diary, 1998-2000, relating to social conditions in Russia (Folder 7)
- Containing the typescript of an autobiographical novel, 1987, relating to political and cultural conditions in the Soviet Union. In Russian (Folder 8)
- clippings and photographs, 1955-1967, relating to visits to the United States and elsewhere (Folder 9)
- Writings, correspondence, printed matter, and miscellany, 1968-2001, relating to political and cultural conditions in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia. In Russian (Folder 10)
- Correspondence, printed matter, and photographs, 1945-2001, relating to cultural and political conditions in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia. In Russian (Folder 11)
- Diaries, correspondence, and photographs, 1963-2002, relating to social and political conditions in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia. In Russian and English (Folder 11)
- Personal documents, 1948-1974. In Russian (Folder 11)
- 2 newspaper issues 2002-2003, relating to political and cultural conditions in Russia. In Russian (Folder 11)
- Writings and sound recordings, 2003, relating to political and cultural conditions in Russia. In Russian (Folder 11)
- Writings and printed matter, 2003-2004, relating to cultural conditions in Russia. In Russian (Folder 11)
- Correspondence and photographs, 1962-2003, relating to political and cultural conditions in the Soviet Union and post-Soviet Russia. In Russian and English (Folder 10)
- Writings and correspondence, 1997-2005, relating to social and intellectual life in Russia. Mainly in Russian (Folder 12)
- Correspondence, writings, and photographs, 1971-2006, relating to cultural conditions in Russia. Mainly in Russian (Folder 13)
- Writings, correspondence, and photographs, 1961-2006, relating to to cultural conditions in Russia. In Russian (Folder 13)